It supports the long-distance travel of more than 1 million people every day, including tourists and business travelers.
Shinkansen Shinkansen is like a river passing through the desert
extremely important
It is the cornerstone of the infrastructure that supports Japan's economy and national development.
The speed of the Shinkansen in just 10 years since it was first broadcasted was quite impressive.
The Story of the Stubborn Father Behind the Birth of the Shinkansen
The Hokuriku Shinkansen, which has had almost no service interruptions since its opening, had an amazing technology to capture the destinations of its passengers.
What's this?
It's so cool!
And the trump card for Japan's economic development...
Quick!
Linear Chuo Shinkansen expected to open in the near future
Sneaking into the undisclosed site of the dream super-express!
How can they dig a tunnel?
This time, we'll learn all about the unknown aspects of Japan's world-famous Shinkansen line.
This is the secret base of Peach Infrastructure Z in Tokyo.
This is where they learn about infrastructure every day.
Hey everyone, let's get started!
Here we go!
Good luck today!
Okay, first of all, let's start with a review of what we've learned in the last few days.
Last time, we talked about drastic measures against earthquakes.
If you remember, we talked about the importance of a decentralized national land formation.
Do you remember what I meant by that?
I remember how we talked about the overconcentration of people in Tokyo.
That's right.
Japan's population and economy are concentrated in Tokyo.
By distributing the population and economy in a well-balanced manner to the regions
Japan will be less likely to collapse in the event of a major disaster.
It is also indispensable to ensure the strength of the nation.
That is what I would like to discuss today.
What is it?
Yes, sir.
Shinkansen.
I take good care of it.
Everyone loves Shinkansen!
Tintin-tintin!
You are singing, aren't you?
Shinkansen is the most used train by the leaders.
I've been commuting to school on the Shinkansen from Shizuoka to Tokyo.
I've taken it every day since I was a high school student.
Since high school.
I use it most often for work.
It's your job.
This time, I would like to focus on the Shinkansen, a train that everyone at Momochlo is always using.
Do you know that the Shinkansen, which we use casually as a means of transportation, actually has a great impact on the development of cities?
The first thing to look at is this... when the first census was taken in the early Meiji era, the top 15 cities in terms of population were as shown below.
Hakodate, Kumamoto, Kagoshima, Kanazawa, Toyama, Wakayama, Tokushima... these were big cities in the past.
What is the current status of these cities?
So there are about 20 big cities now, but they are totally different.
The red line is where the Shinkansen line runs.
In the past, cities were scattered all over the country, but the Shinkansen line has made the surrounding areas more developed.
Unfortunately, cities like Kanazawa, Toyama, Kumamoto, Kagoshima, Tokushima and Okayama, where the Shinkansen did not run for a long time, were not able to become cities because they were too cold in the west.
So if the Shinkansen goes through, those areas will be developed and if not, they will be left behind.
So if the bullet train doesn't go through, the area will be left behind.
So, to put it in an image, the Shinkansen is just like a river in the desert.
So, if you think about it, a bullet train is like a river passing through a desert, where no living things live, but when the river passes through, grass grows around it, trees grow, small animals come, and then larger animals come and an ecosystem is created.
And in such an easy-to-understand way, the bullet train brings nutrients from the people who are responsible for the development of the city, and the surrounding area grows.
But if you think about it, it's a bit like the case of expressways, isn't it?
But the road is good at carrying a lot of things, and the train is good at carrying heavy things, like boxes and boxes of cargo.
Trucks and expressways are convenient for transporting large quantities of goods, but bullet trains are more convenient for transporting people quickly.
But the Shinkansen can carry people quickly.
The bullet train goes about 300 kilometers per hour, three times as fast as the caryl train, and the linear train 500 kilometers per hour.
When the Shinkansen and the train line opens, a lot of people will come and visit the city, which will have an effect on tourism.
In a word, a town will be built.
For example, this is not a Shinkansen, but there is a seat for Shibano-ha campus.
Tsukuba Express. When it opened, it looked like this.
Ten years after the opening of the Shinkansen, a building like this will be built in the same place, so an entire city will be built.
This is the biggest effect of Shinkansen. Infrastructure that can change Japan as a whole.
First of all, let's learn the hidden history behind the birth of the Shinkansen.
This is the person who built the first Shinkansen in Japan.
Universe's first, right?
That's right.
First of all, Tamai, are you ready?
Of course, I've done my research.
Instructor Fujii has prepared a total of four missions for you.
The members in charge of each of them will report their results.
First up is Tamai, who says he's having trouble using his recently acquired pressure cooker.
I, Tamai, will be in charge of today's first mission.
I look forward to working with you.
First of all, do you know what the first bullet train in Japan was?
No, I don't.
But it was the Tokaido Shinkansen.
That's right! The Tokaido Shinkansen!
Shizuoka indeed!
It opened just before the Tokyo Olympics on October 1, 1964!
The maximum speed of the Tokaido Shinkansen at that time was 210 km/h, the fastest in the world!
The fastest in the world!
At that time, there was a huge speed race between countries, and Japan won it by a landslide!
It was wonderful!
This made it possible to complete the journey between Tokyo and Osaka in 4 hours, instead of the 6.5 hours it used to take before.
but it was completed in just 4 hours!
It was the first high-speed railroad in the world and was called the super express of dreams.
After that, the trains were repeatedly improved, and now the maximum speed is 285 km/h.
The time between Tokyo and Osaka has been shortened to 2 hours and 25 minutes
Thank you very much!
The economic effect of the time saving was 250 billion yen per year at that time.
(more than 1 trillion yen in today's value).More than 1 trillion yen in today's value
That's enough to support Japan's rapid economic growth!
The Tokaido Shinkansen, which changed Japan in such a big way
There was a certain person who made it possible.
The answer is in Tokyo Station.
What? Tokyo Station?
It's in Tokyo Station.
The Tokaido Shinkansen arrives and departs from platform 18 and 19.
The person who is inscribed on the monument at the end of the platform is...
Shinji Sogo, the father of the Shinkansen.
He was the president of Japan National Railways (JNR) and led the opening of the Shinkansen.
If you look at this picture, you can see his face like this.
Look at that!
So cute!
They go well together.
Mr. Sogo's motto is also engraved on this monument.
That's right.
Just one flower will bloom and it will be spring under the sky
It means that a single flower announces the arrival of spring.
Behind these words, there is a story of a man who devoted his life to a dream super express.
Peach-colored infrastructure.
Mr. Goh Sung assumed the office of President of Japan National Railways.
JNR was the national organization that operated Japan's railroads at the time.
It is now honored as JR.
In fact, around 1955, when Mr. Zeng Gao became the president of Japan National Railways
Japanese railroads were facing a certain problem.
Here is what was prevalent in Japan at that time
The railroad oacon theory
Oh no!
What does it mean?
Railroads were
In this period of postwar reconstruction and rapid economic growth
Cars and airplanes were the hot sellers at the time
Railroads were out of date
The idea that we should focus on promoting automobiles and airplanes
not only in Japan, but all over the world.
In the midst of all this, the domino effect of the resignation of the president of Japan National Railways (JNR) hit the railroads even harder.
A fire on a train and the suspicious death of the president of Japan National Railways
Accidents and incidents involving Japan National Railways occurred one after another
Three presidents resigned in a row
It was difficult to find a candidate for the next president.
The next candidate for the presidency was Shin Sogo
Mr. Shinji Sogo, who was 71 years old at the time.
By the way, the average life expectancy of men at that time was 63.6 years old
What! That's a long time!
That's quite an old man, isn't it?
So that's where it all started.
Well, Mr. Sogo, the Ministry of Railways used to be called the Ministry of Railways.
And then it became Japan National Railways.
He was a national bureaucrat who joined the Ministry of Railways.
He was a national bureaucrat who joined the Ministry of Railways and rose very high in the ranks.
At that time, there was the South Manchuria Railway
There was the South Manchuria Railway in Manchuria, China at that time.
He was also a director of the South Manchuria Railway.
He was a very important person who supported prewar Japan from the aspect of railroads.
He was a very important person who supported Japan before the war from the aspect of railroads.
But it was a customary event.
At the time, he turned it down once.
But he finally decided to accept the presidency.
As a matter of fact, the day after he took office, there was an article in the newspaper
The day after he took office, there was an article in the newspaper making fun of Mr. Sogo.
Some people even made fun of Mr. Sogo.
However, Mr. Sogo was not just an old man.
was not just an old man.
As soon as he took office, he came up with an unbelievable plan
He came up with an extraordinary plan that no one had expected.
The first bullet train project in Japan!
Yay!
It's wonderful!
Do you think people will accept this project?
Do you think the world will accept this?
But Mr. Sogo was a stubborn old man.
He was a stubborn old man who never gave up.
He doesn't look like that.
He could have said he'd do whatever he wanted.
But when he became president of Japan National Railways...
He wrote in his will that it was his duty to make the bullet train a reality.
He wrote in his will that it was his responsibility to realize the Shinkansen.
He wrote in his will that it was his responsibility to make the Shinkansen happen, and declared that he was prepared to hit the pillow with it.
That's amazing.
If he goes so far as to say that...
Why are you so obsessed with the bullet train, Mr. Sogo?
That's a good question.
I've been told that the future belongs to automobiles and airplanes.
Cars can't carry large numbers of people at once.
If a lot of people come, there's always a traffic jam.
With airplanes, you can't get off the plane on the way.
That's why we have to make sure that the railroads are well connected.
We will not be able to transport people in large quantities and quickly
Japan's economy will not be able to keep going.
That's what he thought.
That's why behind Mr. Sogo's incredibly strong will
Mr. Sogo's incredibly strong will was based on practical engineering judgment based on lightweight calculations.
We definitely need a railroad.
And he had a strong belief that a high-speed Shinkansen train was necessary.
He had a strong belief that a high-speed Shinkansen was necessary.
At the time, the public and the government were all against the Shinkansen
So, in order to realize the project
Mr. Sogo came up with an unbelievable secret plan to realize the project.
First of all...
Convince a big politician to go along with the project.Convincing Big Shot Politicians to Take the Wheel
Here we go!
Ta-da!
Convincing a big shot politician by barging into his house!
Here we are!
The Minister of Construction at that time was a railroad oacon
He was against the Shinkansen.
Mr. Sogo went to see him many times to persuade him.
But each time he was ignored or stood by his appointment.
So Mr. Sogo stormed into the Minister of Construction's house.
He waited day and night until he could see him.
He made many impassioned speeches.
You must have been in the government, like me.
I can't even think about it anymore.
He didn't care what happened to his wife.
How dare you!
Mr. Sogo was over 70 years old at the time... and his opponent was in his 50s.
Mr. Sogo is whipping his old man into shape, and the Minister of Construction is giving him a hard time.
He gave the OK for the Shinkansen project.
He had a tenacious spirit.
He used this tactic to win over the Minister of Construction and other big politicians.
Mr. Sogo gradually gained more and more supporters.
What was needed next was to win the approval of the public, whose hearts had been turned away from the railroad.
So, Mr. Sogo said, "What is it?
What?
He used the media to win over the public's opinion.
He is so young, isn't he?
The media got caught up in the impactful phrase, and the lecture was so successful that there was a standing-room-only crowd.
The keyword used in the newspapers and on TV at that time was "dream super express".
The word spread nationwide and people began to think that the Shinkansen was a dream, and the dream really spread and created public opinion about it.
These efforts bore fruit and construction began in 1959, four years after the inauguration and the Tokaido Shinkansen was inaugurated on October 1, 1964.
That means it was built at such a speed... in only 10 years from the conception.
That's why Japan was so vigorous at that time.
Many people rushed to the platform to catch a glimpse of the completed super express.
Mr. Sogo, the person who made the greatest contribution to the company, was not here. Actually, he resigned a year and a half ago because of the train accident and deficit.
So he was watching what was going on on TV in his apartment.
The Shinkansen became a pillar of Japan's economy, and the railroad, which had been considered an oacon, was reborn as an infrastructure that Japan can be proud of.
As the saying goes, the flower that Mr. Sohgoh made bloom has greatly changed the transportation system of Japan.
And while the Shinkansen has changed Japan's transportation system, changing Japan's transportation system means changing Japan's economy, and changing Japan's economy means raising Japan's national power itself.
Thanks to the Shinkansen, Japan is now a member of the G7 family, one of the seven major industrialized countries, and now ranked third in the world in terms of the Gdp.
The success of the Shinkansen in Japan has also influenced the world's railroads.
The success of the Shinkansen in Japan influenced the world's railways, and high-speed trains were born in France and Germany, putting an end to the theory that railroads were for cars.
Even today, trains run all over the world, and behind the history of these trains lies the passion of Japan's stubborn fathers.
Interviews with young employees involved in infrastructure with their passion No!
Mr. Kaku has loved structures such as dams and bridges since he was a student.
In the construction industry, you are given a lot of responsibility from your first year, so I think it's very challenging in that sense, but I think it's also very rewarding.
Mr. Kaku is in charge of highway renewal work.
This is a project to introduce new technology into the highway renewal work.
The company as a whole is popular for improving the existing technology itself, so I think it's interesting to work in this area as well.
I think this is one of the interesting aspects of my job.
Right now, we are in the stage of acquiring various knowledge and skills with the support of many people.
I would like to become an engineer who can pass on my skills to the next generation.
Good luck! Young Infrastructure Warrior
This is a concept that was announced by Kukuei Tanaka in 1972.
It is called the "Theory of Archipelago Remodeling.
It was proposed by Kukuei Tanaka about 50 years ago, following the great success of the Tokaido Shinkansen line.
The Japanese Islands Remodeling Theory proposed by Kukuei Tanaka about 50 years ago
With an eye on the future development of Japan, he proposed a 10,000-kilometer expressway network and a 9,000-kilometer Shinkansen network.
and a 9,000-kilometer Shinkansen network.
Although the realization of this plan has begun to move forward
The current realization rate of expressways is 130%, while that of Shinkansen is only 30%.
while the Shinkansen is at a standstill at only 30%.
Shinkansen construction has been on the decline since the period of rapid economic growth.
However, in recent years, the construction of regional Shinkansen lines has finally progressed, and the atmosphere is gradually changing.
The next mission
Investigate the Hokuriku Shinkansen, the star of regional development
This mission was conducted by Mr. Takagi, who is rumored to be addicted to firefly squid.
Takagi will be in charge of the next mission crew!
Not too much individuality!
It's like a circular train.
It sure looks like a bullet train!
Even though it's the Yamanote Line Loop Line.
First of all, please take a look at this.
Here's the ranking of the most popular domestic travel destinations.
The 2015 number one is a prefecture that was outside the top 10 the year before.
Where do you think it's going to be?
Well... this is the trend.
Can you guess?
Seino...
Ishikawa
Ishikawa Prefecture, right?
Ishikawa.
is the correct answer.
It's true, from the flow of the conversation.
It's Ishikawa Prefecture, isn't it?
Ishikawa Prefecture became No. 1 in March 2015, when the Hokuriku Shinkansen
Hokuriku Shinkansen connecting Tokyo and Kanazawa.
We're on it!
It used to take more than 4 hours to get there, but now it takes only 2.5 hours.
It has become a popular travel destination.
To be honest, I had never said I wanted to go to Kanazawa in conversation with my friends.
That's right, it never came up.
Once the Shinkansen came through, we went.
I went right away.
We did, didn't we?
In the first year of operation, the number of Shinkansen passengers tripled compared to the previous limited express era.
In addition, accommodation reservations in Ishikawa Prefecture increased 1.85 times compared to the previous year!
It generated a huge economic effect in terms of tourism in the surrounding prefectures as well.
The Hokuriku Shinkansen Line has had such an enormous effect.
In fact, the plan itself has been in the works since the 1970s.Actually, the plan itself has been in the works since the 70's.
There was a reason why it took 40 years to open for business
There was a unique reason for the Hokuriku Line
First of all, please take a look at this
This super steep gradient
Between Annaka Haruna Station and Karuizawa Station
there is a slope with a height difference of 650 meters!
Oh, it's a thrill to see!
It's high!
The Hokuriku Shinkansen Line runs through very rough terrain.
The Hokuriku Shinkansen Line runs through very rough terrain, and there are many difficult places with elevation differences such as this.
On top of that, it took a long time to construct the long tunnel.
What's more...
And the biggest obstacle...
What do you think of when you think of Hokuriku?
Seafood
Sea
It's all about food, isn't it?
Seafood
All you want to eat is fish.
What is it about Hokuriku that makes it so unique?
It is one of the heaviest snowfall areas in Japan.
When it snows heavily, it sometimes looks like this.
In fact, the conventional train service has been suspended for 17 days in a row
All day service was suspended for 17 days in a row due to snow.
All day for 17 days?
That's a real problem, isn't it?
But you know, the Hokuriku Shinkansen has been in service for 8 years.
The Hokuriku Shinkansen has been suspended only 3 days due to snow.
Why?
Three days.
What do you mean?
How in the world did they overcome the snow?
It's because of the infrastructure technology unique to snow country!
Peach Infrastructure Get!
How does the Hokuriku Shinkansen Line cope with snow?
We interviewed Mr. Yamamori of the Railway Transportation Bureau in Kawakita Town, Ishikawa Prefecture.
In these areas, a common type of snow plow is used.
There is a gap of about 60 centimeters between the Shinkansen rails and the ground where we are standing now.
The snow is stored there.
The Hokuriku Shinkansen line route is mostly passed by tunnels and 40% by elevated bridges.
Elevated bridges are structures in which the tracks are placed at a higher position than the ground level.
Elevated bridges are often seen on ordinary trains other than the Shinkansen.
The tracks are exposed, so they are unarmed against snow, so countermeasures are necessary.
This is the most popular structure for snow protection.
I see.
The tracks are raised 60 to 75 centimeters above the surrounding area, as if the tracks were covered with snow shoes.
Snow accumulates in the grooves on the sides, so it doesn't disturb the Shinkansen.
The Hokuriku Shinkansen is mainly used around Kanazawa Station where there is little snow.
It is also used on the Tohoku Shinkansen where snow is scarce.
However, in areas where there is more snow, the grooves can become buried or even frozen.
So here is a more powerful countermeasure
Oh, freezing!
Sprinklers
Sprinklers are installed next to the tracks to spray water and melt the snow.
It's a very effective way to prevent icing in areas with a lot of snow.
Well, then it's possible they're spraying water on us without us knowing.
It was wet right away.
This is the main method used on the Masetsu Shinkansen.
It's only 15% effective on the Hokuriku Shinkansen line between Nagano and Kanazawa.
The reason why the section is so short is because of the conditions for using sprinklers.
There is a condition, too.
The water to melt the snow has to be pulled from the river, so there has to be a river nearby.
The Hokuriku Shinkansen Line has only a few rivers that are suitable for this purpose.
In addition, the cost of fuel to heat the water so that it doesn't freeze adds up.
That's right.
Okay, so here's the infrastructure 9
The Hokuriku Shinkansen, which has a lot of snowfall, does not have a method of storing snow that is common on other Shinkansen lines or a method of melting it with sprinklers, which is difficult.
It is difficult to use sprinklers to melt the snow on the Hokuriku Shinkansen
So, they created an original hardening mirror.
What is it like?
What is the original hardened mirror that the Hokuriku Shinkansen has created that neither stores nor melts snow?
What kind of original hardening mirror is it?
I'll ask you to answer with an illustration.
Can you guess?
I have a hint.
Yes.
Yes, sir.
Can I have a hint?
I wrote it down, but that's okay.
Please give me a hint.
Please.
Yes, sir.
That's what I meant.
Neither save nor dissolve.
That's what I mean.
Yes, sir.
From Aaryn.
Yes, ma'am.
Yes, sir.
It's a rice ball.
This is a bullet train.
And here, on the bottom.
It has a fan like a fan.It had a fan like a fan.
The wind is coming out from below.
So that the snow won't come near it anymore.
You'd need an awful lot of fan.
You need a lot of wind power.
Next, Mr. Tamai.
Hi, Tamai.
You look like a cockroach.
It's so cute!
Cute!
Shinkansen
It's not about the track.
but the bullet train itself.
Oh, I see.
Where there seems to be a lot of snow...
Water is let out from the Shinkansen.
I see.
Lastly, Momota-san, please.
If you can't hoard it
I'll catch it
Ha-ha-ha
Oh, but I understand
What do you mean by "catch"?
Catch the snow
And with this hint from Renni-chan
If you manage to melt the snow you catch
make it spray outside.
Let's take a look at the correct answer right away.
Peach-colored infrastructure set
This is the descent bridge.
The railroad tracks are right here.
Here are the tracks.
This is the track.
Normally, it's separated by a single wall.
But there's another wall on the outside, right?
Here.
Zoom in on the space between these walls.
Here it is.
It's open. It's open.
Yes, it's open.
Oh!
This hole in the floor is the key. See how this hole is used here?
What's that?
What's this?
It's for exclusive use.
Yes, that's right.
It was a method of making a hole in the viaduct and sending snow toward the hole with a snowplow
That's not what I heard!
Snow plow!
Snow plow
The snow flung by the snowplow hits this outer wall and falls down through the hole.
That's amazing!
The previous snow plows were designed to shovel snow.
The newly developed snow plow throws the snow away with precision.
Outside.
The key point was to combine a newly designed elevated bridge
This system was developed for the Hokuriku Shinkansen, and is used for 14% of the Nagano-Kanazawa line.
Under this hole is also the Shinkansen site, so there is no problem to drop snow.
After all, there are many difficulties in building the Shinkansen line.
When facing these difficulties, new technologies are developed and used all over the country.
This is how new technology is created and used all over the country.
By the way, when the snow plowmen work at night after the last train, where are they during the daytime?
I am, aren't I?
I thought so.
This is the Kawakita snow removal base.
This is where the snowplows for the Shinkansen are kept.
Actually, this base is a part of the Shinkansen tracks during operation.
There is a device so that the snowplows do not interfere with the operation of the Shinkansen.
The track is
Wow!
More? What? They're sticking them together?
Oh, up there?
Oh, my God.
They're on top of each other.
Wow.
There's a device called a traversing device.
This is the main line that the Shinkansen runs on.
And then the car goes over the main line
And put them on the detention line over there.
This device connects the main line and the track where the snowplows are kept
The snowplows are moved between the main line and the tracks where the snowplows are kept
without interrupting the passage of the Shinkansen.
Multiple snow removal bases are set up along the route
to efficiently fight the snow in the limited time before the first train leaves.
It's very well thought out.
Not only for the tracks, but also for the maintenance of the trains.
It's essential to take measures unique to an area with heavy snowfall.
Yes, this is the trial inspection shed.
This is where the Shinkansen trains that have completed their high-speed runs are inspected every two days.
Here, in addition to the usual inspections of pantographs on the roof of the Shinkansen, etc., the following inspections are carried out
This is a fixed oil contact nozzle. Hot water of about 60 degrees Celsius is sprayed out from this nozzle.
The system is designed to melt snow around the wheels by spraying hot water of about 60 degrees Celsius.
Snow on the wheels can cause accidents on high-speed Shinkansen trains.
That is why Shinkansen trains take warm showers like this to melt the snow.
Thanks to such daily care, the Hokuriku Shinkansen has almost no service suspensions due to snow.
The regional Shinkansen lines that support Japan have infrastructure technology that overcomes the climate and topography of each region.
That's all. Well done, Mr. Takagi. Thank you very much.
The Hokuriku Shinkansen currently runs between Tokyo and Kanazawa, but it is not yet complete.The Hokuriku Shinkansen Line, currently running between Tokyo and Kanazawa, is not yet complete.
Sasaki investigates the challenges of the Hokuriku Shinkansen for the future.
Next mission. Wait a minute.
I'm sorry.
I'm doing everything right. Sorry, it's my fault.
Next mission. Next mission.
Sasaki will be in charge of the crew.
So, the Hokuriku Shinkansen opened in 2015. As Neruni-chan told me earlier, construction is still continuing.
The Hokuriku Shinkansen is scheduled to open in the spring of 2024, and will go beyond Kanazawa to Tsuruga in Fukui Prefecture.
That's amazing. It's going to extend again. It's going to extend that way.
This time, I have discovered a remarkable infrastructure that will be the first of its kind in Japan.
The first of its kind in Japan. Here it is.
This is the Kuzuryugawa Bridge. The bridge spans the Kuzuryugawa River that runs through the northern part of Fukui City, Fukui Prefecture.
First in Japan?
It is the first in Japan. Now, here is Infrastructure 9.
This Kuzuryugawa Bridge looks like an ordinary bridge, but it actually has a special structure that is the first of its kind in Japan.
What are the features of this bridge?
What is the structure of the Kuzuryugawa Bridge, the first of its kind in Japan for a bullet train?
You can see it in the picture, too, if you look closely. There you go.
I know now.
But it's not so easy to find the answer in this picture.
I know it.
I'll give you a big hint.
Let's take a look at it from the side.
Yes, this is the bridge.
Look, look, I'm going to give you a big hint.
What? What?
Now then, let's see the correct answer.
Peach-colored infrastructure!
Mr. Yoshioka from the Japan Railway Transportation Agency is here to show us Japan's first bridge.
The Kuzuriu River Bridge is the first Shinkansen and roadway bridge in Japan.
The Kuzuriu River Bridge is Japan's first Shinkansen and roadway bridge that combines the Shinkansen and roadway.
The correct answer is that the Shinkansen and cars run together!
I've never seen this bridge before!
Amazing, isn't it?
Yes, when the Hokuriku Shinkansen opens in Tsurugama, you will be able to experience a bridge like this where the Shinkansen and cars run together.
And you were walking on it.
Yes, it seems that pedestrians can also go there.
That's amazing!
So how did this bridge come about?
This prefectural road project was planned for a different location.
As the plan for the Shinkansen line became more detailed, it was decided to build the prefectural road together with the Shinkansen line.
The prefectural road was planned to be built together with the Shinkansen line.
Originally, Fukui Prefecture was planning to build a new bridge to ease traffic congestion on the road.
But when the Hokuriku Shinkansen extension was discussed, they decided to build a bridge together.
We are good friends.
If we didn't get along, one of us would have to give up the other.
This bridge is mine, right?
This bridge has great advantages.
It will shorten the construction period, reduce the cost, and we can build it without polluting the clean environment of the river.
That's why we built this bridge together.
The biggest advantage of this bridge is that it is environmentally friendly.
This river is home to a valuable fish called the arale gako.
The river itself is designated as a national natural monument.
We decided to build them together because the number of pillars in the river might increase if we build the Shinkansen and the road bridge separately, which would have a negative impact on the river.
By building them together, we were able to reduce the number of pillars and create a bridge that is friendly to the environment of the river.
The road was opened to traffic in late October last year.
Since the road was opened in late October last year, we have been hearing more and more about the usefulness of the bridge to the people of Fukui City.
We hope to contribute to the local community with the opening of the Shinkansen line as well.
The Kuzuryugawa Bridge was created through a partnership between Fukui Prefecture and the Japan Railway Transportation Agency.
It was truly a dream bridge connecting infrastructure and the future!
I'm looking forward to it! We can go farther, can't we?
Fukui Prefecture and the rest of the world will be even more excited!
No doubt about it!
Furthermore, the Hokuriku Shinkansen line is currently under construction to Tsuruga.
The real goal is not Tsuruga, but beyond it!
It's a place we often go too.
How far will it go?
It will go all the way to Osaka.
Like that?
Is that great?
Like this.
That's great.
You mean we can go through there?
Yes! It means people in Kanazawa will have better access.
That's great.
We always go this way.
Yamanote Line!
Yes! A double network will be completed.
By connecting to Osaka.
Even if there is a problem with the Tokaido Shinkansen
The Hokuriku Shinkansen will be able to go from Tokyo to Osaka.
It will also make it easier for people in Kanazawa to get to Osaka.
It's a good thing, isn't it?
Furthermore, if you look at the national network
Tokyo is connected to Tokaido, Hokuriku, Joetsu and Tohoku.
However, Osaka is virtually served by only one line, Tokaido and Sanyo.
That's why the gap between Osaka and Tokyo has widened so much.
The reason for this disparity is that Osaka is served by only one train line
That's why the gap between Osaka and Tokyo has widened.
However, if the second line goes through, the ratio will be 1:2.
The gap will surely narrow.
Does this mean that the project will be completed up to Osaka?
It will be completed up to Osaka.
But I keep telling the government that it should not end there.
This is where Mr. Fujii's new Hokuriku Shinkansen project comes in.
I'd like to connect the Shinkansen that has come this far to Kansai Airport.
That would be very convenient.
This is definitely a good idea!
In the world, there is a collaboration between airport and Shinkansen, like Schiphol.
As soon as you get off at the airport, there is a Shinkansen underground, and you can go anywhere in Europe.When you get off at the airport, there's a Shinkansen right underground, and you can go anywhere in Europe.
That's why it's so convenient, but we don't have it in Japan yet.
That's what I thought.
So when people from all over the world come to KIX, they can go to Kanazar in an instant.
That's great!
I'm working hard to convince people to do it.
I hope you can make it happen.
My dream has expanded again!
I can't wait to go on this trip!
Interview with a young employee who is passionate about infrastructure
This is Young Infrastructure.
Taku Tanaka has been working as an engineer for 10 years at a company involved in civil engineering and construction projects.
He is currently in charge of construction of a sewerage system that discharges rainwater into the sea and rivers to prevent flood damage in the Yokohama Station area.
Mr. Tanaka manages the progress of the construction work.
What is the appeal of this job?
I am happy when I see a project completed exactly as I imagined it would be.
I am also moved when I see that I have made a difference for everyone.
That's a great feeling.
I hope that the people of the town will be able to spend their time safely.
There is a lot of damage caused by natural disasters.
I hope that the construction work will help to reduce such damage.
I hope that the construction work will help to reduce the damage caused by natural disasters, and that everyone's safety will be further protected.
Good luck, young infrastructure warriors!
Let's go to the last mission of the day, the last mission of the day is here.
I've been researching the Linear Shinkansen because I heard that there is a leader of the Linear Shinkansen who is slowly becoming more and more interested in everything about the Linear Shinkansen.
Pan-pan-pan-pan!
I, Momota, will be the clerk in charge of today's final mission.
I look forward to working with you all.
By the way...
I wonder if any of you have ridden the Ninia before.
From Mr. Takagi over there.
Yes. I haven't.
No, I haven't.
Yes, there is.
Yes, you do.
Yes, it is.
I've been on the Lumia bullet train.
I've had a ride on Lumia's bullet train... and it was a shock.
It was so fast that I felt like I was on the move.
They were conducting an experiment in Yamanashi, where the distance was 40 km, and it took only 9 minutes.
Nine minutes.
It might have been about 9 minutes.
That's amazing!
I'd like to share my rich experience with you this time.
Yes.
I've done a thorough investigation of Lumia as an infrastructure.
What's the difference from Shinkansen?
I'll get to the point.
What are the advantages of Lumia?
First of all, you all know how fast it is.
Speed.
Right?
Lumia will be passing through now, so please take a good look.
Good night.
What?
That's fast!
That's right, isn't it?
This is a speed of 500 kilometers per hour.
The test speed was 603 kilometers per hour.
It runs on tires for a while after starting traffic.
But when the speed exceeds 150 km/h, it switches to levitation using magnetic force.
Wow! Is that right?
Yes, sir.
It's flying.
We're flying?
This is the superconducting magnetic levitation system you all know.
No, I don't know.
I don't know.
I've never heard of it.
It's the first time I've heard of it.
Well, the simple explanation is that it uses a lightweight, powerful magnet to levitate the vehicle.
This really makes it run super fast!
Magnets
I've ridden around on one myself.
I can feel the moment it really starts to float.
You can?
It's like a whoosh.
I can tell when the train has switched.
I would like to compare it with the current Tokaido Shinkansen.
From Shinagawa in Tokyo to Nagoya by Tokaido Shinkansen, it takes 1 hour and 26 minutes at the fastest.
The fastest time from Shinagawa to Nagoya on the Linear Line is 40 minutes.
Wow, that's amazing!
40 minutes is about the time from Shinjuku to Hachioji by train.
To put it more simply, rice is cooked in normal mode.
Oh, that's great!
That's great.
That's great!
This is the best part!
If you eat a bento lunch, it'll be on in no time.
We don't have time to sleep.
No time to sleep.
Well, one of the biggest advantages of the Linear Line is the economic effect generated by this extraordinary speed.
According to the Ministry of Land, Infrastructure, Transport and Tourism, when the Shinagawa-Osaka line opens, the economic effect over 50 years is expected to be
The Ministry of Land, Infrastructure, Transport and Tourism estimates that the economic effect of the Shinagawa-Osaka line will be 17 trillion yen over 50 years.
I don't understand anymore.
I'm so hopeful.
I'll take that train, won't I?
Now that that's all said and done, aren't you all curious?So, doesn't this make you wonder
Where will the Linear Line go through?
I'm curious.
Please tell me.
Shin-Yoko
Shin-Yoko is not good anymore!
You don't have to go to Shin-Yokohama early!
Here's the route you're all anxious to take
This way!
That way!
That's right!
The route will go through Tokyo, Kanagawa, Yamanashi, Nagano, and other three interregional areas.
This is of great significance as infrastructure.
This is a
Double network
Ping-pong double network.
Linear and Tokaido Shinkansen to connect Tokyo-Nagoya-Osaka
Plans are underway to double Japan's main arteries
Indeed
I see.
Nearly 60 years have passed since the Tokaido Shinkansen started operation
It is important to build a double network with the Linear Line to prepare for age-related deterioration and large-scale disasters such as the Nankai Trough Earthquake.
It is important to build a double network with the Linear Line.
The construction work for the opening of the Linear Line, which is highly anticipated as such infrastructure, is now steadily underway.
Let me take you to the construction site.
Yes, this is a certain construction site for the Linear Line, you see the big hole?
It's about 36 meters long.
Wow, look at that.
It's huge!
Now let's take a look at Infrastructure 9.
This hole has an indispensable role to play in the construction of the Linear Line.
What is it?
A huge hole 36 meters in diameter and 100 meters deep, essential for the opening of the Linear Line.
What is its role?
Okay, yes, more than that.
The place where the body of the Linear Line is kept will be erected.
It will be broken
break
Put up a new one.
Then I'll make a lot more
To make a lot, you need space, so you stand up the finished linier.
This hole is not one, it's many
Yes, Ernie.
Station.
No, it's not. We've infiltrated a rare construction site that's never been shown on TV before to investigate.
Peach-colored infrances
We've come to Machida City, Tokyo, the site of the giant hole. The man who will show us the way is...
I'm Mr. Miyauchi, a member of the Central Shinkansen construction team at jr Tokai.
Construction is scheduled to begin in 2018, and the hole is being excavated to a depth of 110 meters below the surface.
It is a vertical hole to transmit a shield machine, which is a special machine to build underground tunnels.
The shield machine is a heavy machine that digs tunnels while rotating its tip like a drill.
The correct answer is that it is a hole to send the machine in and out of the ground during construction.
Wow, they can dig tunnels!
And the reason why we need so many holes is because we need to connect the tunnels by moving the shield machines through multiple holes.
And the reason why we need so many of these holes is because we need to connect the tunnels by digging through multiple holes with the shield machines.
Maintenance and ventilation of the machines are also done through these holes.
That's great!
The name of this hole is an emergency exit.
So the hole will be closed when the Linear Line is open?
After the line is open, the hole will be used as an emergency exit by installing stairs and elevators to allow people to enter and exit in case of an emergency.
A real emergency exit.
Of course, it's very hard to dig this deep.
It's a lot of work, isn't it?
Normally, there is groundwater underground, so at a depth of 110 meters, most of the construction work will be below groundwater.
As we dig deeper, groundwater will gush up and harm the construction work.
Therefore, we needed to prevent groundwater intrusion.
This is a revolutionary method called "Pneumatic Light Damage Method".
What's that?
A huge concrete bottom called a "light loss" is sealed so that it is in contact with the ground.
A sealed space is created so that it is in contact with the ground.
By sending compressed air into that space
By sending compressed air into that space, it is possible to dig while preventing the intrusion of groundwater.
For example, an empty cup is placed upside down in a water tank.
Then, a space filled with air will be created inside the cup.
We can actually create that in the lower part of the vertical shell.
So we can create a dry environment and then advance the plant deep underground.
But deep underground, in a sealed and pressurized space, it's like diving in the deep sea.
It's like diving in the deep sea.
It's impossible for a person to stay there for a long time.
You can rest assured.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Please don't worry.
Anyway, I understand.
It's okay to pose like that.
We were shown a special new system that avoids danger.
I was shown to a side office, not inside the emergency exit
Inside the room
What on earth are all these adults doing, operating the controllers so enthusiastically?
What are you doing?
What the workers here are doing is to ensure the safety of underground light-damage construction work.
They are remotely operating the excavators that you can see on the monitor.
The excavator you see on the screen is a light-damage excavator.
There is a rail on the top, and the excavator is moving along the rail.
In order to safely proceed with the work in the space where compressed air is being sent.
About 10 small shovels are remotely operated.
Skilled workers are digging day and night in shifts.
They are digging day and night.
It looks like he's relaxing a little bit.You seem awesomely a little relaxed.
I think it looks like a fun game, but...
Even though it is a machine, the digging is being done by human hands.
The tunnel is currently being dug up to about 80 meters out of the 110 meters.
The Ageo Yamada emergency exit is scheduled for completion in 2024.
Next year.
After that, shield machines will pass through here, and the tunnel will be dug.
I can't wait for the completion of the Linear Line.
I can't wait!
That's all for now.
Well done, Mr. Nomoto!
Thank you.
When it opens, Tokyo, Nagoya, and Osaka will be able to come and go in a little over an hour.
Tokyo, Nagoya, and Osaka will be able to come and go in a little over an hour.
These three metropolitan areas will become one of the largest mega-regions in the world.
They're going to become one giant city.
What happens when that happens?
Even if you live in Nagoya, you can get there in 40 minutes.
You don't have to stick to Tokyo anymore.
In terms of living in Tokyo
Certainly.
Even if Tokyo is where you work
you can live in many places.
According to our Kyoto University simulation analysis
According to our Kyoto University simulation analysis, it is predicted that the population will become very dispersed.
Certainly.
Even if we consider various projects for decentralization
The Linear Shinkansen has been calculated to be the most effective for decentralization.
We, experts in the field, strongly hope that the Linear Shinkansen will open as soon as possible.
The theme of the next issue of Momo-iro Infrastructure Z is ports.
The origins of Japan's logistics lie in a ship that was called a "moving general ministry building.
We will also take an in-depth look at the latest ports that are key to Japan's economy!
Please look forward to the broadcast on Sunday, August 6 at 11:00 a.m.!
Peach-colored Infrastructure Z is broadcast with the cooperation of the sponsors you see here.
Yes, hi.
I'm going to go to the cafe.
This is the central café.
Wow.
Please come to the cafe.
It's cute.
It's so cute.
Amazing.
It's so cute!
It's good, it's good, it's good.
Thank you so much.
It's my first time.
You're so cute.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Bon appétit.
Thank you.
Oh, man.
Agenia.
I Tokaido.
I can't.
Take my picture.
You can take a picture, too, Kan-chan.
Take a picture of me at the bottom.
Like you're celebrating.
I get it.
I'm starting to feel like I did the research.
May I?
Thank you very much.
Domping is different.
Domping is unreasonable.
Thank you very much.
[Applause]